[
    {
        "question": "New Zealand lies on the boundary of what two tectonic plates?",
        "correct": "Australian and Pacific",
        "wrong1": "African and Antarctic",
        "wrong2": "Eurasian and Indo-Australian",
        "wrong3": "Indian and Pacific"
    },
    {
        "question": "Leaving Nelson we now travel to the northern most area of the South Island. Where are we?",
        "correct": "Cape Farewell",
        "wrong1": "Cape Goodbye",
        "wrong2": "Nelson Cape",
        "wrong3": " Northern Cape"
    },
    {
        "question": "Auckland is situated between two harbors. What is the geographical name for this configuration?",
        "correct": "Isthmus",
        "wrong1": "Plateaus",
        "wrong2": "Mesas",
        "wrong3": "Basins"
    },
    {
        "question": "Auckland is situated between which two harbours?",
        "correct": "The Manukau, and The Waitemata",
        "wrong1": "The Kaipara and The Bluff",
        "wrong2": "The Manukau and the Kaipara",
        "wrong3": "The Bluff and The Waitemata"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Maori name for the Bay of Islands town Russell?",
        "correct": "Kororareka",
        "wrong1": "Waikouaiti",
        "wrong2": "Omakau",
        "wrong3": "Waihola"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is not one of Dunedin City offshore islands?",
        "correct": "Black Island",
        "wrong1": "White Island",
        "wrong2": "Green Island",
        "wrong3": "Taieri Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "What small island off the coast of Dunedin has the same name as an island off the coast of North Island?",
        "correct": "White Island",
        "wrong1": "Taieri Island",
        "wrong2": "Black Island",
        "wrong3": "Green Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which New Zealand city would you find the building known as the Beehive?",
        "correct": "Wellington",
        "wrong1": "Auckland",
        "wrong2": "Christchurch",
        "wrong3": "Otago"
    },
    {
        "question": "New Zealand's first capital was in Russell in the Bay of Islands but was moved to which NZ town?",
        "correct": "Auckland",
        "wrong1": "Wellington",
        "wrong2": "Christchurch",
        "wrong3": "Otago"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Otago town sits on a shore of a lake whose name means 'Spreading water' in Maori? ",
        "correct": "Waihola",
        "wrong1": "Wanaka",
        "wrong2": "Omakau",
        "wrong3": "Waikouaiti"
    },
    {
        "question": "Starting in the 1890s, the gold rush was located closest to which Otago town?",
        "correct": "Lawrence",
        "wrong1": "Arrowtown",
        "wrong2": "Cromwell",
        "wrong3": "Clyde"
    },
    {
        "question": "The discovery of what natural resource made Dunedin become the most populated city in New Zealand in the late 1800s?",
        "correct": "Gold",
        "wrong1": "Iron",
        "wrong2": "Coal",
        "wrong3": "Diamond"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the first town in New Zealand to be considered a city?",
        "correct": "Dunedin",
        "wrong1": "Invercargill",
        "wrong2": "Nelson",
        "wrong3": "Kaikoura"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Maori name for New Zealand?",
        "correct": "Aotearoa",
        "wrong1": "Whakatu",
        "wrong2": "Te Tihi-o-Maru",
        "wrong3": "Otautahi"
    },
    {
        "question": "St Kilda, Woodhaugh, Caversham and Forbury are all suburbs of which South Island city?",
        "correct": "Dunedin",
        "wrong1": "Nelson",
        "wrong2": "Kaikoura",
        "wrong3": "Christchurch"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these are not suburbs of Dunedin?",
        "correct": "Coversham",
        "wrong1": "St Kilda",
        "wrong2": "Woodhaugh",
        "wrong3": "Forbury"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these are a commercial ski field in the Queenstown area?",
        "correct": "The Remarkables",
        "wrong1": "Treble Cone",
        "wrong2": "Cardrona",
        "wrong3": "Whakapapa"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the longest river in the South Island?",
        "correct": "Clutha",
        "wrong1": "Whanganui",
        "wrong2": "Waikato",
        "wrong3": "Waiau"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many stars on the New Zealand flag?",
        "correct": "4",
        "wrong1": "3",
        "wrong2": "5",
        "wrong3": "50"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which town is a self-declared republic in the Taranaki region?",
        "correct": "Whangamomona",
        "wrong1": "Whangarei",
        "wrong2": "Whanganui",
        "wrong3": "Wanaka"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main religion of New Zealand?",
        "correct": "Christianity",
        "wrong1": "Islam",
        "wrong2": "The Ratana Church",
        "wrong3": "Buddhism"
    },
    {
        "question": "What bay is commonly known as Murderers Bay?",
        "correct": "Golden Bay",
        "wrong1": "Tasman Bay",
        "wrong2": "Hawke Bay",
        "wrong3": "Karamea Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What northern town has a steam locomotive on display, but has never had a railway?",
        "correct": "Kaitaia",
        "wrong1": "Ahipara",
        "wrong2": "Cape Reinga",
        "wrong3": "Mangonui"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Maori name for New Zealand is Aotearoa. What does this mean in English?",
        "correct": "Land of the Long White Cloud",
        "wrong1": "Land of the Many",
        "wrong2": "New World",
        "wrong3": "Green world"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately, what percentage of the population of New Zealand is Maori?",
        "correct": "10%",
        "wrong1": "15%",
        "wrong2": "5%",
        "wrong3": "20%"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which South Island town can a great big monument of a fish be seen when you drive in?",
        "correct": "Rakaia",
        "wrong1": "Whaikorero",
        "wrong2": "Tangihanga",
        "wrong3": "Kaikorero"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the southern hemisphere's deepest cave system?",
        "correct": "Nettlebed",
        "wrong1": "Clearwater",
        "wrong2": "Lechuguilla",
        "wrong3": "Jewel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the beachside town located to the west of Kaitaia?",
        "correct": "Ahipara",
        "wrong1": "Karanga",
        "wrong2": "Waiata",
        "wrong3": "Whare kai"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Maori name for Stewart Island?",
        "correct": "Rakiura",
        "wrong1": "Nikau",
        "wrong2": "Aroha",
        "wrong3": "Hikoi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the main seaside suburb of Christchurch?",
        "correct": "New Brighton",
        "wrong1": "Latimer",
        "wrong2": "Victoria",
        "wrong3": "Inner City West"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest city by population on the South Island?",
        "correct": "Christchurch",
        "wrong1": "Hamilton",
        "wrong2": "Tauranga",
        "wrong3": "Invercargill"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which town is found on the shores of the Bay of Plenty?",
        "correct": "Whakatane",
        "wrong1": "Queenstown",
        "wrong2": "Dunedin",
        "wrong3": "Napier"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the popular bay in Timaru?",
        "correct": "Caroline Bay",
        "wrong1": "Goldern Bay",
        "wrong2": "Hawke Bay",
        "wrong3": "Jackson Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of New Zealand's largest city?",
        "correct": "Auckland",
        "wrong1": "Wellington",
        "wrong2": "Rotorua",
        "wrong3": "Christchurch"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these features does NOT describe the kiwi?",
        "correct": "Low Hearing",
        "wrong1": "Flightless",
        "wrong2": "Endangered",
        "wrong3": "Nocternal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following towns/cities has Tim Shadbolt been the mayor of?",
        "correct": "Invercargill",
        "wrong1": "Queenstown",
        "wrong2": "Dunedin",
        "wrong3": "Rotorua"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the New Zealander who allegedly flew around the same time, if not before, the Wright brothers?",
        "correct": "Richard Pearse",
        "wrong1": "Willie Tarah",
        "wrong2": "Lizbeth Case",
        "wrong3": "Noelle Merv"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main ingredient of the ANZAC biscuit?",
        "correct": "Rolled oats",
        "wrong1": "Apple",
        "wrong2": "Dates",
        "wrong3": "Sugar"
    },
    {
        "question": "The three main islands of New Zealand are North Island, South Island and this island.",
        "correct": "Stewart",
        "wrong1": "Chatham",
        "wrong2": "White",
        "wrong3": "Great Barrier"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river runs through the city of Hamilton?",
        "correct": "Waikato",
        "wrong1": "Whanganui",
        "wrong2": "Clutha",
        "wrong3": "Buller"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of NZ's longest range of mountains?",
        "correct": "Southern Alps",
        "wrong1": "Andes",
        "wrong2": "Alps",
        "wrong3": "Northern Andes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What street holds the record for being the steepest in the world?",
        "correct": "Baldwin Street",
        "wrong1": "Ballance Street",
        "wrong2": "Boulcott Street",
        "wrong3": "Bowen Street"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many volcanoes are there in Auckland?",
        "correct": "53",
        "wrong1": "45",
        "wrong2": "41",
        "wrong3": "35"
    }
]